RICARDO ALBERTO PÉREZ CANDELAS

ricardo.pcan@gmail.com 5568583198 http://richartl.github.io/

Full-stack software developer with 4+ years industry experience specializing in back-end development and devops. Born and race in Texcoco, Mexico State, I enjoy play and follow college football and flag football, amateur guitar and drums player, mindfull and successfull books.



WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS MVC REST

JAVASCRIPT NODE.JS JQUERY BOOTSTRAP REACT.JS BACKBONE.JS REACT NATIVE

DATABASE MYSQL POSTGRESQL NOSQL ORM

DEVOPS AWS DIGITALOCEAN DOCKER DOCKER COMPOSE CI/CD

BACKEND REST JSON API DESIGN PATTERNS TDD

PROJECT AGILE GITHUB TEAMWORK LEADER GITFLOW GITHUB FLOW



EMPLOYMENT

Team Leader, Mellow Consulting

2017-09 — Present

Tech Team leader for Mellow Consulting, lead a team of 8 people

- Lead a tech team of 8 people
- Implement workflows and process for development
- Talk with clients for create products
- Plan, propose and implement digital solutions for client requirements with designers and marketing teams
- Teach and propose solutions to developer team
- Apply agile techniques for meets and project teams

Agile Lead SCRUM React Native PHP AWS Node, js React. JS Redux Workflow CI/CD

Ruby on Rails Developer, Tech Leader, Vinco Orbis

2016-11 — 2017-09

Ruby developer with Ruby on Rails Framework for a education projects

- Lead a team of 2 people
- Teach to junior developers best practices
- Use TDD and CI/CD
- Use docker for create development environments

Lead Ruby on Rails Ruby CircleCi CI/CD TDD Rspec SCRUM

PHP Developer, Vinco Orbis

2015-04 — 2016-11

PHP developer on Wordpress, Prestashop and vanilla PHP projects

- Create templates
- Paticipate in a team for international client

PHP Wordpress Prestashop

Software Developer, Coordinación General de Formación e Innovación Educativa (CGFIE), Instituto Politécnico Nacional (IPN)

2015-01 — 2015-12

I participated on numerous Vanilla PHP projects for teach to IPN community, I used git, gitlab, docker

- I worked on a local PHP MVC framework for standarized team workflow
- I installed a basic CentOS server for local use
- I proposed use the github workflow for developer team and created many manual for best development and deploy practices

PHP Linux MVC Codeigniter Git Gitlab Docker

Trainee Code, Feather México

2014-08 — 2015-01

Trainee developer, I participated on Ruby on Rails projects with PostgreSQL and Agile development techniques

- Participated on project for a big ensurance company
- I understood the MVC and Design Patterns

Agile Ruby Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL SCRUM HTML CSS MySQL PHP



Tech Leader and Backend Developer, Creator API Product for build interactive lessons for kids with multimedia resources from Youtube, Khan Academy Magsiterial, Google Images Education Ruby Docker Python Microservices Test Unit Rspec Continuous Integration Continuous Delivery	
Devops and backend developer, khan-lite-backend 2017-06 — 2017-06 Microservice for serve resources from Khan Academy Lite installation, build with ruby and docker containers Education Ruby Docker Microservices Ruby on Rails API	
Devops and backend developer, wiki-download Microservice for serve pdf from Wikipedia article, build with python and docker containers Education Docker Microservices Django Django Rest Framework API	2017-06 — 2017-06
Back-end developer, Grubertek API RESTFUL API for Grubertek PHP PHPUnit Vagrant Test Unit Continuous Integration Continuous Delivery API	2016-09 — 2017-04
Developer, SudoVerbs Bash console utility for learn english verbs Bash Shell Education	2017-05 — 2017-05
Developer, tech lead, team lead, Royal Licoreria a Domicilio Platform for deliver alcohol with hibrid and native mobile apps React Native Redux Node MySQL Loopback App IOs Android	2017-09 — Present
Developer, tech lead, team lead, Simulador Reto ENARM Simulator for ENARM test, this simulator helps to medics to study for ENARM test React Redux Node MySQL Loopback Node Docker Docker Compose	2017-09 — Present
Developer, tech lead, team lead, Autounion This platform helps to agencies and customers to sell and find options for buy a car React Redux Node PostgreSQL Loopback Node Docker Docker Compose Django	2017-09 — Present



EDUCATION

BSCS, Universidad Autónoma del Estado de México Branch on Software Development

2010-06 — 2014-12



WRITING

El porque las pruebas unitarias no sirven, Medium

2017

La diferencia entre rake y rails, Medium

2017

Un paso obligado para ser un desarrollador 'Pro', Medium

2017



ReactJS Basic Course, to ReactJS

• I teached to 10 people the first steps2017

Docker Basic Course, Docker Meetup Course CDMX the first steps to Docker technology

• I spoke front of 100 people teaching2017